{"Topic": "Banking", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "icwise Questions - Banking and RBI related Questions", "op1": "Bank of India", "op2": "Bank of Baroda", "op3": "Punjab National Bank", "op4": "Corporation Bank", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following public sector banks has the largest number of branches in foreign countries?", "op1": "Bank of India and New Bank of India", "op2": "Punjab National Bank and New Bank of India", "op3": "Allahabad Bank and United Bank of India", "op4": "Punjab National Bank and Bank of Rajasthan", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The only merger of two public sector banks took place between -", "op1": "Bank of Maharashtra", "op2": "Bank of Baroda", "op3": "State Bank of Saurashtra", "op4": "Union Bank of India", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following banks was inaugurated by Mahatma Gandhi in 1919?", "op1": "Punjab National Bank", "op2": "Bank of India", "op3": "Andhra Bank", "op4": "Canara Bank", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "After State Bank of India, which of the following banks has the largest number of offices?", "op1": "Only 1", "op2": "Only 2", "op3": "Both 1 and 2", "op4": "All the three", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following rates are reviewed by the RBI at the time of periodical review of the policy?", "op1": "Rate of interest which is competitively changed in relation to other banks", "op2": "Floating rate of interest charged by banks", "op3": "Low rate of interest in the initial period which goes up subsequently", "op4": "Higher rate of interest in the initial period which goes down subsequently", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "What are teaser loan rates charged by banks?", "op1": "Interest rate swap", "op2": "Input devices", "op3": "Sedimentary", "op4": "Zero Hour", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following terms is used in banking field?", "op1": "Easy Monthly Instalment", "op2": "Equal Monthly Investment", "op3": "Equated Monthly Instalment", "op4": "Equated Mortgage Investment", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Expand the term EMI as used in banking/finance sector?", "op1": "Reserve Bank of India", "op2": "Government Of India", "op3": "State Bank of India", "op4": "Securities and Exchange Board of India", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Bank rate is decided by which of the following?", "op1": "Home loans", "op2": "Personal loans", "op3": "Auto loans", "op4": "Reverse mortgage loans", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "With which of following types of loans are teaser rates related?", "op1": "Money", "op2": "Marginal", "op3": "Message", "op4": "Mobile Phone", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "What does M in M-Banking Facility being offered by banks to their customers, stand for?", "op1": "Only 1", "op2": "Only 2", "op3": "Only 3", "op4": "All 1, 2, and 3"}, {"Question": "Which of the following is/are true about the Sub-Prime Crisis?", "op1": "A - 4; B - 1; C - 2; D - 3", "op2": "A - 3; B - 4; C - 1; D - 2", "op3": "A - 2; B - 1; C - 4; D - 3", "op4": "A - 3; B - 1; C - 4; D - 2", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Match the following mergers of banks", "op1": "Mumbai", "op2": "New Delhi", "op3": "Kolkata", "op4": "Dehradun", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "At which of the following cities is the Head Office of Reserve Bank of India located?", "op1": "Cash reserves", "op2": "Deposit reserves", "op3": "Excess reserves", "op4": "Momentary reserves", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The reserves held by Commercial Banks over and above the statutory minimum, with the RBI are called", "op1": "1955", "op2": "1957", "op3": "1962", "op4": "1965", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "In which year was the Imperial Bank of India rechristened as State Bank of India?", "op1": "Reserve Bank of India", "op2": "Union Finance Commission", "op3": "Union Ministry of Finance", "op4": "Union Ministry of Commerce", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The Imperial Bank of India, after its nationalization came to be known as", "op1": "Reserve Bank of India", "op2": "State Bank of India", "op3": "United Bank of India", "op4": "Indian Overseas Bank", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Regional Rural Banks are sponsored by", "op1": "Nationalised Commercial Bank", "op2": "Reserve Bank of India", "op3": "State Bank of India", "op4": "Government of India", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which is the country\u2019s third largest private sector lender whose name has been officially changed to the Axis Bank ltd. ?", "op1": "1935", "op2": "1947", "op3": "1949", "op4": "1952", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "In which year was the Reserve Bank of India established ?", "op1": "Local Indian Bank Offered Rate", "op2": "London-India Bureau Of Regulations", "op3": "Liberal International Bank Official Ratio", "op4": "London Inter Bank Offered Rate", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Expand the term LIBOR as used in financial banking sectors?", "op1": "RBI", "op2": "SIDBI", "op3": "NABARD", "op4": "SEBI", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the apex institution which handles refinance for agriculture and rural development in India?", "op1": "1969", "op2": "1972", "op3": "1973", "op4": "1975", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Regional Rural Banks were established in the year \u2013", "op1": "Acting as banker to the Government", "op2": "Keeping of Foreign Exchange Reserve", "op3": "Issuing of one rupee notes and coins", "op4": "Regulating credit in the country", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following is not the function of the Reserve Bank of India ?", "op1": "Recovery of bad loans", "op2": "Regulation of Foreign Exchange", "op3": "Fixation of interest rates", "op4": "Acquisition of small banks", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "With which of the following is SARFAESI Act 2002 related?", "op1": "Red Label ATMs", "op2": "White Label ATMs", "op3": "Green Label ATMs", "op4": "Blue Label ATMs", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "ATMs that are owned and managed by non-banking entities are known as -", "op1": "Rs. 100", "op2": "Rs. 5", "op3": "Rs. 10", "op4": "Re. 1", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "In which denomination were India's first bimetallic coins issued in the year 2009?", "op1": "50%", "op2": "35%", "op3": "25%", "op4": "15%", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The share of State Govt in the capital of Regional Rural Bank is \u2013"}, {"Question": "o see G.K. Questions on Marketing"}, {"Question": "o see G.K. Questions on Economy"}, {"Question": "o see Important Information on RBI"}]}